POST-MORTEM  //  AUTOPSY FILE
VOICEOVER  //  CAPTIONS SYNCED
Two. The specific calculation that
overflowed wasn't even
needed after liftoff. It was a leftover,
a routine that
only mattered on the launch pad, left
running into flight
for a rocket where it served no purpose
at all.
Dead code, still armed.
Three. That conversion had no protection
on it — no
check to catch a number that was too
large, no
safe fallback. Some values in the system
were protected.
This one was deliberately left
unprotected, to save
processing power, based on an assumption
that the number
could never get that big. On Ariane 4,
that assumption
was true. On Ariane 5, no one re-checked
it.