POST-MORTEM  //  AUTOPSY FILE
VOICEOVER  //  CAPTIONS SYNCED
But at one point, the code needed to
hand that
value to another part of the system that
expected
something smaller — a sixteen-bit
number. A far smaller
box.
And here is the entire disaster, in one
idea: on
// VISUAL: A BIG AMBER NUMBER BEING POURED INTO A SMALL
BOX THAT...
Ariane 4, the sideways speed never got
big enough to
overflow that little box. The rocket was
slower off the
pad. The number always fit.
Ariane 5 was a different animal. More
powerful. It built
up horizontal speed far faster than its
predecessor ever
could.
Thirty-seven seconds into the flight,
that sideways speed
// SIDE-BY-SIDE: ARIANE 4 GENTLE CURVE VS ARIANE 5 STEEP
CURVE; THE...
climbed past the largest value the small
box could hold.