POST-MORTEM  //  AUTOPSY FILE
VOICEOVER  //  CAPTIONS SYNCED
Ariane 5 went on to become one of the
most
// PAUSE
successful rockets in history — it flew
for another
twenty-seven years. They found the bug.
They fixed the
redundancy. They asked the questions.
But the first one paid for that lesson
in thirty-seven
seconds and three hundred and seventy
million dollars.
Every disaster starts as a decision that
made sense at
// BEAT
the time. That's the whole job of this
channel —
to go back and find the exact moment the
sense
ran out.
I'm going to keep putting failures on
this table. If
// WORDMARK
you want to be here when I do —
subscribe,
and I'll see you at the next one.