POST-MORTEM  //  AUTOPSY FILE
VOICEOVER  //  CAPTIONS SYNCED
Four. Both the main and backup units ran
identical
software. So the redundancy — the whole
point of having
two — was an illusion. A backup only
helps if
it can fail in a different way. This one
was
guaranteed to fail in exactly the same
way, at exactly
the same instant.
Put those together and the shape of it
is clear.
// BEAT. TONE STEADIES
This wasn't the story of a bad
programmer. It was
the story of a good assumption that
quietly stopped being
true — and a system with no one left to
notice.
The code wasn't wrong for Ariane 4. It
was wrong
for the rocket it was actually bolted
to. And nobody
had asked the question, because it had
never needed
asking.