POST-MORTEM  //  AUTOPSY FILE
VOICEOVER  //  CAPTIONS SYNCED
The number didn't fit.
In that instant, the software did what
it was written
// THE VALUE HITS THE CEILING. MONO ERROR TEXT FLICKERS:
OPERAND ERROR
to do when it hit an impossible
conversion. It flagged
an error — and it shut the whole
navigation unit
down.
The backup unit? It was running the
exact same code,
reading the exact same too-large number.
It had failed a
fraction of a second earlier, for
exactly the same reason.
Two independent systems. One shared
flaw. Both gone. And
// TWO UNITS ON SCREEN; BOTH GO DARK, ONE AFTER THE
OTHER. BEAT
the rocket was now flying blind.
CHAPTER 3 — THE COLLAPSE
With both navigation units offline, the
failed system did
// TONE DROPS. THIS IS THE MOMENT
one last thing before it died. Instead
of sending flight
data, it sent a diagnostic error code —
raw numbers,
meant for engineers on the ground, never
meant for the
flight computer.