POST-MORTEM  //  AUTOPSY FILE
VOICEOVER  //  CAPTIONS SYNCED
POST-MORTEM
On the fourth of June, 1996, a rocket
left the
The $370 Million Bug — How One
Line of Code Destroyed a Rocket
THE ANATOMY OF HOW THINGS FALL APART
ground in French Guiana.
Thirty-seven seconds later, it tore
itself apart in the
// HELD BLACK. FAINT LAUNCH-PAD RUMBLE
sky.
No one was hurt. There was no sabotage.
No storm.
// AMBER EKG LINE DRAWS ACROSS... FLATLINES... THEN THE
CRASH SPIKE....
No faulty wire, no cracked weld, no
engine that failed.
The rocket worked perfectly. Every bolt,
every valve,
every gram of fuel did exactly what it
was built
to do.
It was destroyed by a number. A single
number, in
// PAUSE
a piece of software that wasn't even
supposed to be
running — code that had already done its
job, copied
over from an older rocket because it had
never once
failed.