POST-MORTEM  //  AUTOPSY FILE
VOICEOVER  //  CAPTIONS SYNCED
This is how a decade of work and three
hundred
and seventy million dollars came apart
in less time than
it takes to read this sentence.
This is POST-MORTEM.
// INTRO STING: WORDMARK SNAPS IN
CHAPTER 1 — THE SETUP
Ariane 5 was Europe's bet on the future.
Its predecessor, Ariane 4, was one of
the most reliable
// ARCHIVAL-STYLE STILLS: ESA, THE ASSEMBLED LAUNCHER,
BLUEPRINT...
rockets ever flown — Europe's workhorse,
a machine that
put more than half the world's
commercial satellites into
orbit. But it was getting old, and it
wasn't big
enough for what was coming next.
So the European Space Agency spent
nearly ten years and
around seven billion dollars building
its successor.
Ariane 5 was taller, heavier, and far
more powerful —
a rocket designed to carry the biggest
payloads of the
coming century.