POST-MORTEM  //  AUTOPSY FILE
VOICEOVER  //  CAPTIONS SYNCED
Flight 501 was its very first launch.
The maiden voyage.
// STAT CARDS, MONOSPACE: ~10 YEARS · ~$7 BILLION ·
MAIDEN FLIGHT...
On board sat four scientific satellites
called Cluster — a
mission years in the making, built to
study the Earth's
magnetic field. Irreplaceable.
Now — a rocket is only as smart as the
// BEAT
computer flying it. And that computer
needs to know one
thing above all else: which way is up.
How is
it tilted, how fast is it turning, where
is it
pointed. That job belongs to a component
called the
Inertial Reference System.
Ariane 5 carried two of them — a main
unit
// SIMPLE DIAGRAM: THE SRI FEEDING ORIENTATION DATA TO
THE MAIN...
and a backup — constantly measuring the
rocket's motion
and feeding it to the flight computer,
so the engines
could steer.