POST-MORTEM  //  AUTOPSY FILE
VOICEOVER  //  CAPTIONS SYNCED
Thirty-seven seconds. That's all it
took.
// THE EXPLOSION. THEN CUT TO SILENCE. HELD BLACK
Ten years of work. Around three hundred
and seventy
// MONO, SLOW COUNT-UP: T+00:37 · ~$370,000,000 LOST
million dollars of rocket and
satellites. Gone — over a
number that was too big for its box.
CHAPTER 4 — THE AUTOPSY
An inquiry board took the failure apart.
And the
// AMBER CHAPTER CARD: "THE AUTOPSY". SHIFT FROM WHAT
HAPPENED TO WHY
uncomfortable truth is that no part of
this was bad
luck. Every link in the chain was a
decision.
One. The navigation code was reused from
Ariane 4 without
// THE FINDINGS APPEAR ONE BY ONE, MONO LIST, AMBER
TICKS
being re-tested against Ariane 5's
actual flight profile.
It was trusted because it had never
failed — but
it had never flown this rocket.