POST-MORTEM  //  AUTOPSY FILE
VOICEOVER  //  CAPTIONS SYNCED
Here's the decision that matters. When
the engineers wrote
the software for that system, they
didn't start from
scratch. Why would they? Ariane 4's
version had flown for
years without a single fault. It was
trusted. It was
proven.
So they reused it.
And that decision — the safe one, the
sensible one
// ON SCREEN, MONO: "REUSED FROM ARIANE 4 — 0 FAILURES".
AMBER...
— is what killed the rocket.
CHAPTER 2 — THE CRACKS
To understand why, you need one small
piece of how
computers hold numbers. I'll keep it
painless.
Inside that navigation software was a
value tracking the
// CLEAN ANIMATED EXPLAINER, CHARCOAL + AMBER
rocket's sideways speed — its horizontal
velocity. The
program stored it in a large, roomy
format: a
sixty-four-bit number, able to hold a
huge range of
values.