POST-MORTEM  //  AUTOPSY FILE
VOICEOVER  //  CAPTIONS SYNCED
But the flight computer didn't know
that. It was still
waiting for orientation data, and it
took those error
numbers and read them as if they were
real —
as if the rocket were violently off
course.
So it did its job. It tried to correct.
It
// GARBAGE DATA FLOODING INTO THE FLIGHT COMPUTER; THE
HORIZON...
swung the engine nozzles hard over to
fix a problem
that did not exist.
The rocket obeyed. It pitched sharply,
at full power, into
// THE NOZZLES SLAM TO FULL DEFLECTION
an angle it was never built to survive.
The aerodynamic
forces hit it like a wall.
The boosters began to tear away from the
main stage.
// SIGNAL RED ENTERS FOR THE FIRST TIME
And the moment the rocket sensed itself
breaking apart,
its automatic self-destruct did the only
thing left to do
— it detonated the vehicle, high over
the launch site,
before the wreckage could reach the
ground.